<system>
	<name>Kepler-31</name>
	<rightascension>19 36 05</rightascension>
	<declination>+45 51 11</declination>
	<distance>1113</distance>
	<star>
		<mass>1.21</mass>
		<radius>1.22</radius>
		<planet>
			<name>Kepler-31 b</name>
			<name>KOI 935.01</name>
			<name>KIC 9347899 b</name>
			<list>Confirmed planets</list>
			<radius>0.118469</radius>
			<period>9.61</period>
			<semimajoraxis>0.09</semimajoraxis>
			<transittime errorminus="0.006" errorplus="0.006" unit="BJD">2454992.141</transittime>
			<description>This planet candidate was discovered with the Kepler spacecraft. Because there are multiple phenomena that can create a signal that looks similar to a planetary transit, the candidates have to be confirmed with another method. For Kepler-31 the planetary nature of the companions has been confirmed by transit timing variations, caused by other planets in the system, and a stability analysis. However, the mass of the planets is not well constrained yet. There are at least two other unconfirmed planets in the system.</description>
			<discoverymethod>transit</discoverymethod>
			<lastupdate>12/08/06</lastupdate>
			<discoveryyear>2012</discoveryyear>
			<new>0</new>
			<temperature>771.9</temperature>
		</planet>
		<planet>
			<name>Kepler-31 c</name>
			<name>KOI 935.02</name>
			<name>KIC 9347899 c</name>
			<list>Confirmed planets</list>
			<radius>0.391860</radius>
			<period>20.86</period>
			<semimajoraxis>0.16</semimajoraxis>
			<transittime errorminus="0.007" errorplus="0.007" unit="BJD">2454974.191</transittime>
			<description>This planet candidate was discovered with the Kepler spacecraft. Because there are multiple phenomena that can create a signal that looks similar to a planetary transit, the candidates have to be confirmed with another method. For Kepler-31 the planetary nature of the companions has been confirmed by transit timing variations, caused by other planets in the system, and a stability analysis. However, the mass of the planets is not well constrained yet and is just an upper limit. There are at least two other unconfirmed planets in the system.</description>
			<discoverymethod>transit</discoverymethod>
			<lastupdate>12/08/06</lastupdate>
			<discoveryyear>2012</discoveryyear>
			<new>0</new>
			<temperature>605.5</temperature>
		</planet>
		<name>Kepler-31</name>
		<temperature>6340.0</temperature>
	</star>
</system>
